If you all want to know about Aditya Birla Sun Life
Insurance Company Limited's Vision Life
Income Plan,
then check the video description and
you will get the link to the Vision Life Income Plan video.
If you want to know about life insurance,
mutual funds, pension plans, ULIP plans, and
government savings schemes along with post office schemes,
then
stay connected to the channel because
you get videos on these topics on the channel
and to stay connected, you have to
like and share the video, subscribe to the channel and turn on
all the notification bells so
that you keep getting alerts for all the latest
videos. Hello everyone, a
very warm welcome to all of you. You are watching You
The Real. I am your own personal
advisor Amitraj Sharma. So, in today's video, as per the
comment of Mr. Ji, we will learn about the
Vision Plan of Birla Sun Life Insurance Company Limited.
This company is
now known as Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance. This plan was
launched by the company in 2011. So, you must have understood
that this plan came a long time ago, now it must have been
withdrawn and all its benefits must have been withdrawn.  The
details will not be available now, so
we can talk about the main benefits
like death benefit, where if a
monthly addition is added along with the guaranteed death benefit, then
that is available, along with that an
enhancement to monthly addition is also available
if the policyholder dies within the policy term,
right, or if it happens
within the premium payment term.
Guaranteed death benefit means the sum assured that
you choose while taking the plan. Monthly
addition means a fixed percentage of your sum assured
divided by 12.
Now this monthly addition keeps accumulating during the guaranteed
survival benefit period or the
premium payment term,
which you get on completion of the premium payment
term. Now this
enhancement to monthly addition is
available to you only when your GSB i.e.
guaranteed survival benefit period is more than 21 years
and your monthly
addition which is more than 21 years
As soon as your premium payment term
is completed or you can say that the guaranteed
survival benefit term is completed, then
you get the survival benefit.
In the form of survival benefit, you
get guaranteed survival benefit along with that
monthly addition which the company keeps announcing in the plan from time to time,
if it does, then
mainly it keeps getting added, along with that you
get announcement to monthly addition.
After getting the survival benefit, you get
guaranteed maturity benefit at the end of the policy term.
After getting the guaranteed maturity benefit, the policy gets terminated.
Guaranteed maturity benefit in the plan
means the sum assured which is
chosen at the time of taking the plan. Let us take an example, let us assume that
Mr. A, whose age is 35 years, must have
taken Vision Plan of Bila Sun Life, in such a case the policy
term would have been 65 years
because the cover in this plan remains till the age of 100 years, that is,
this was a whole life
plan.  Suppose he has
taken a Guaranteed Survival Benefit term of 25 years and the
premium payment term is taken for the same number of years as the Guaranteed Survival Benefit term, then the
premium payment term is 25 years, if he has taken a sum
of ₹1 lakh then he would have paid an annual premium of ₹563.
Now to
know the rate of monthly addition, we have to see
in which band our sum amount is falling. If our
sum amount is more than ₹1 lakh but
less than ₹4 lakh then it is coming in Band 2.
This band information is
given in your policy document. If you
read it carefully then you will know that how much our
Guaranteed Survival Benefit will we get for a sum of ₹1, it is
mentioned in the table here. Our premium
payment term was 25 years i.e. Guaranteed Survival
Benefit term and our sum amount was of Band 2,
so on a sum amount of ₹1 we will get ₹1  293, that is, the
rate of Guaranteed Survival Benefit is 129.99
sum assured, if we take
out 9.30% then
this amount will be 32250 which the policy holder will
get at the end of the policy term, I am
sorry, it will be received at the end of the
premium payment term, now during this premium payment term,
monthly additions keep accumulating, the
company has the right, now the premium payment
term has been kept equivalent to the Guaranteed Survival Benefit
term here in this plan, that is,
whatever monthly additions will be accumulated during the Guaranteed Survival Benefit term,
it will be received at the
end of the Guaranteed Survival Benefit term
and the rate of monthly addition is
not fixed, it can change from time to time
because at the end of every financial year the
company can announce it separately, so our
Guaranteed Survival Benefit term here is of
25 years, that is, it is more than 21 years, so
in such a case, the sum assured of 1000  The sum assured is
₹5000000
annually, which means what is the monthly addition rate?
4.5% of the sum assured. Our sum assured is
₹1 lakh. If we take out 4.5% and
divide it by 12, it will amount to ₹37.50 paise,
which will be received every month and will keep getting
added within the policy.
If the rate remains this much, then now we know that there are
300 months in 25 years, so we
multiply 9750 paise by 300, then
our monthly addition amount becomes 8250.
Now the declaration to monthly addition has been given to us here
and we know that if the
guaranteed survival benefit term is
more than 21 years and the monthly addition has been
added for more than 21 years, only then we
get the declaration monthly addition. Right, now
our guaranteed survival benefit term is 25
years, which is more than 21 years.  This is the ads
rate detail which is written on the top of the screen
and our sub-mach is of band 2, so our
announcement rate which will be applicable per year will be
applicable for 5. Now it is clearly written here that
Guaranteed Survival Benefit Term Beyond 21
Years, that is, the enhancement period which will be calculated here,
we will subtract 21 from 25, it will become
4, how many times it will increase
four times and how much each time 55
%, so what is the total 5 4 20 20%,
whose monthly addition will it increase, so we took out
20% of 281 250, it came to 562, so
as soon as the premium is paid continuously for 25 years, that is, the
guaranteed survival benefit term
ends, then now here Mr. A will get the
survival benefit, guaranteed
survival benefit of
3250, award monthly addition of
8250 and enhancement to monthly addition of 562, if we
add these then  The amount will be ₹ 6750.
If the rate of monthly addition
remains 4.5%, then if the rate changes then
this will also change. Now when this survival
benefit is received after completing 25 years, then the
remaining policy term which is left is
40. Now the sum which was left was ₹ lakh.
Now the remaining policy term of 40 years is
left. If the
insurance section is included in this then.  When will the nominee get Rs. lakh
after receiving the survival benefit,
if death occurs.  You will get Rs. 1 lakh,
which means the premium payment term has been
completed and all benefits have been received.
After that, no premium is to be paid. If the
remaining policy term expires within 40 years, then the
nominee will get it. If these
40 years are completed and the wife survives, then even then the
company will give her Rs. 1 lakh as maturity amount. The
plan will be closed. So, this is the way the
benefits of this plan are.
Based on the information I could get, I have told you
that it can be calculated in this way. If
you have this policy, then
go to the insurance company's website and
log in with the policy number. There,
how much benefit you are getting every year, the
monthly addition will definitely be shown there. If it is
not there, then
take help of their customer support because the plan has been
withdrawn a long time ago, so
we will not be able to share more information.
Thank you, take care of yourself all.